# Sufyan Saleem

Date of Birth: 4 Jan 1996 Marital Status: Single

Address: Asgårdvegen 23, D3, 9016 Tromsø Website: https://sufvansaleem.net/ Email: sufvansalim94@gmail.com

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am a 28 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward to a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with a friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Aido AS

## July 2021 - present

# **Full Stack Developer**

Working for this service provider agency, which provides smart solutions for managing rotations and shift planning. My main roles include developing Hybrid Mobile Application, Web Application.

#### Linknbit

#### Dec 2020

# MERN Stack Developer

Worked as part time project based remote MERN Stack developer.

#### Missog

- Ecommerce Store

**Under Development** 

#### Decklaration

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

#### MERN Stack Engineer

Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

#### Mertium

Similar to Bloomberg.

Software Engineer

# I developed the frontend

React, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB, Digital Ocean

Remote, Norway

Remote

Remote

based on template

HTML, CSS, Less, React

### Medtigo

Provides services for hospitals

I developed the Backend in Nodejs, Express, MSQL, Sequelize, Node mailer, Security for XSS and SQL Injection

### Linknbit

#### Jan 2019 – May 2020

Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

Islamabad, Pakistan

#### Kyla App

- It is a Mobile App to know your laws
- Recommended actions
- Contact lawyer with location and details
- Paid and Unpaid Feature

#### Global Aviation System

For Central African Republic

Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Node mailer, Geolocation, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection

I am worked on parts of backend Node JS, Express, Sequelize CLI, PassportJS & Azure SQL, Swagger

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play

## **Dynasty Unleashed Models**

- Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers
- Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will

#### Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- User can register, select products, add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.
- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base

#### **Yogurt App**

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate.

#### **SmartsAid**

NGO App for refuges

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Flements

2022 - FYP

Nudging based on users preference

 Developed an app, where user vital data is taken from Fitbit device and nudged with notifications to not be inactive and recommended activities based on user's preferences.. Expo, Firebase, Python, Flask, Rest API, React Native Paper

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2021 <u>Chord Paper</u>

NodeJs, Python, Shell

 Implementation of the chord paper, a scalable peer to peer lookup for internet applications.

• A key value store.

2010 RuneScape RPG

Java

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you.

**Note:** For more projects checkout the website mentioned in the header of the resume.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Science

UiT, Tromsø (Aug 2020 – Dec 2022)

Internet of things and Al Specialist Course PIAIC, Islamabad (2019), Only First Quadrant

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

# **SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE**

#### **Specialities**

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

#### **Social Links**





#### Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo
Vanilla JS, Node JS, Express
Mongoose, Sequelize
Firebase, Mongo DB, MySQL,
PostgreSQL
HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI
Git, Heroku, Netlify, Digital Ocean,
Amazon
Rest, GraphQL, MVC
Bash, Rust
Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

# **LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES**

Languages English Urdu Pashto, Basic Norsk

**Hobbies** 

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding, Boxing, Cross Country Skiing